Guide to the photograph album Iraq, Egypt, Yemen compiled by L. Wells from the Hisham Khatib Collection AD.MC.030_ref158
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection
1934 - 1936
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
Khatib, Hisham, Mr.
Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1938
AD.MC.030_ref158
33 Leaves - 36 gelatin silver photographs
Created by officer Les Wells while he served with the Medical Service at the RAF General Hospital in Hinaidi as part of the "British Forces in Iraq" RAF Command and whilst he was stationed in Egypt between 1934 and 1936 - part of the Hisham Khatib Collection.
Object Digital copy only - ref158
Content Description
A photograph album containing 36 gelatin silver prints of sites and people in Iraq and Egypt between 1934 and 1936.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Aden, Yemen; Egypt; Regional/National Dress; Royal Air Force; Landscapes; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Military/Soldiers; Khatib, Hisham, Mr.
- Front Cover of Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection, 1934-1936; ref158_000001; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Inside of the front cover of Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection, 1934-1936; ref158_000002; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  English Writing
- Aerial view of RAF Aboukir air base., 1934-1936; ref158_000003; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Royal Air Force; Coast; Military/Soldiers; Seas; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Abu Qir, Egypt
- A waterfall in Sulav, Northern Iraq, 1934-1936; ref158_000004; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Waterfalls; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- A bridge over a river in Sulav, Iraq., 1934-1936; ref158_000005; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Bridges; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Iraq; English Writing; Rivers; Landscapes
- Zab River in Iraq, with mountains in the background., 1934-1936; ref158_000006; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Rivers; Iraq; Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; English Writing; Water
- A woman wearing a veil carrying a basket on her head, with boys surrounding her., 1934-1936; ref158_000007; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Women; Boys; Girls; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Outdoors; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Photographic Prints; Children; Group Portraits; Food; Workers
- Three men sitting outdoors., 1934-1936; ref158_000008; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Outdoors; Men; Children; Regional/National Dress; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Arabic Writing; English Writing; Furnishings; Signs/Signposts; Signs/Signposts; Boys; Children
- Several men standing around two men sitting on the ground., 1934-1936; ref158_000009; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Men; Regional/National Dress; Outdoors; Outdoors; Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
- A portrait of a man with a mustache wearing a keffiyeh., 1934-1936; ref158_000010; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Men; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress
- A man harvesting dates from a palm tree., 1934-1936; ref158_000011; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Palm Trees; Workers; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Men; Food
- Mausoleum of Umar Suhrawardi, Baghdad., 1934-1936; ref158_000012; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Tombs; Buildings; Palm Trees; Baghdad, Iraq; Architecture; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cemeteries; Religious Sites
- Mausoleum of Umar Suhrawardi, Baghdad., 1934-1936; ref158_000013; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Tombs; Architecture; Buildings; Baghdad, Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Cemeteries; Religious Sites
- A Nairn Transport vehicle crossing the Syrian desert., 1934-1936; ref158_000014; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Buses; Deserts; Transportation; Syria; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- An aerial view of Taq Kasra (Archway of Ctesiphon)., 1934-1936; ref158_000015; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Buildings; Architecture; Iraq; Deserts; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- A statue in the Antoniadis Garden in Alexandria, Egypt., 1934-1936; ref158_000016; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Gardens; Statues/Sculptures; Alexandria, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- A statue in the Antoniadis Garden in Alexandria, Egypt., 1934-1936; ref158_000017; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Statues/Sculptures; Gardens; Alexandria, Egypt; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- HMS Enterprise off the coast of Aden., 1934-1936; ref158_000018; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Military/Soldiers; Boats/Ships; Navy; Seas; Aden, Yemen; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- The mediterranean fleet in Alexandria harbour., 1934-1936; ref158_000019; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Seas; Boats/Ships; Ports; Coast; Alexandria, Egypt; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Mediterranean Sea; Transportation
- Stanley bay in Alexandria., 1934-1936; ref158_000020; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Alexandria, Egypt; Beaches; Men; Advertisements; Shops; Buildings; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Advertisements; Signs/Signposts
- Nouzha garden in Alexandria., 1934-1936; ref158_000021; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Egypt; English Writing; Gardens; Palm Trees
- Nouzha garden in Alexandria., 1934-1936; ref158_000022; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Portrait of a child leaning against a wall., 1934-1936; ref158_000023; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Girls; Children; Individual Portraits; Outdoors
- House on the wall, Montazah., 1934-1936; ref158_000024; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Alexandria, Egypt; Egypt; Buildings; Houses; Architecture
- House on the wall, Montazah., 1934-1936; ref158_000025; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; English Writing; Architecture; Buildings
- A body of water with trees and rocks in the background., 1934-1936; ref158_000026; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Landscapes; Water
- A boy and a girl standing outdoors., 1934-1936; ref158_000027; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Group Portraits; Children; Boys; Girls; Regional/National Dress; Outdoors
- A waterfall with a building in the background., 1934-1936; ref158_000028; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Waterfalls; Buildings; Landscapes
- A rocky hillside., 1934-1936; ref158_000029; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Landscapes
- Men and horses by a body of water., 1934-1936; ref158_000030; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Horses; Men; Water; Animals
- A group of five men carrying guns., 1934-1936; ref158_000031; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Group Portraits; Guns; Horses; Turbans; Weapons; Swords/Knives; Regional/National Dress; Animals; Men
- A man riding a camel with the Pyramid of Khafre in the background., 1934-1936; ref158_000032; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Camels; Men; Palm Trees; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Animals; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt
- Great Sphinx of Giza., 1934-1936; ref158_000033; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Giza, Egypt; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Egypt; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Monuments/Memorials
- Blank Page, 1934-1936; ref158_000034; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Interior of RAF Halton House., 1934-1936; ref158_000035; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Architecture; Houses; Chandeliers; Furnishings; Aylesbury, England, UK; Furnishings; Military/Soldiers
- Blank Page, 1934-1936; ref158_000036; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Blank Page, 1934-1936; ref158_000037; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Blank Page, 1934-1936; ref158_000038; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Left: A concert poster for The Exiles. Right: A group of performers on stage wearing white tuxedos., 1934-1936; ref158_000039; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Group Portraits; Men; Tuxedos; Bow Ties; Pianos; Musical Instruments; Performing Arts; Advertisements; Costumes; Theater
- Top: A group photo of men in uniform. Bottom: A street view., 1934-1936; ref158_000040; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Group Portraits; Outdoors; Men; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Architecture; Royal Air Force; Street Lamps
- Top: Aerial view of a harbour. Bottom: Ship leaving a harbour with covered cannons in the foreground., 1934-1936; ref158_000041; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Boats/Ships; Military/Soldiers; Cannons; Seas; Architecture; Buildings; Weapons; Transportation; Ports
- Blank Page, 1934-1936; ref158_000042; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- A man in a chemistry lab with bottles on the shelf in the background., 1934-1936; ref158_000043; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Men; Chemistry; Lab Coats; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Chemistry; Scientific Equipment; Lab Coats; Laboratories
- Palm trees., 1934-1936; ref158_000044; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; English Writing; Palm Trees
- Inside of the Back Cover, 1934-1936; ref158_000045; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Back cover of Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection, 1934-1936; ref158_000046; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)